一千多年前
More than a thousand years ago,
中国分裂成三个国家  不停地打仗
China broke into three kingdoms at war.
打仗首先要吃饱
Food became the paramount necessity.
有个皇帝为了不让战士饿肚子
To feed his soldiers,
在军队安插摸金校尉官衔
one emperor invented 'Mojin Xiaowei'
这官衔是干嘛的呢
They are official tomb robbers
就是到处探勘古墓
borrowing gold from the dead...
破门开棺  跟死人借钱买粮食
for the livings.
摸金校尉规矩森严  凡开大墓
They have strict rules to follow:
必须在地宫墓室的东南角点上一只蜡烛
Before a coffin is opened
方可开棺摸金
a candle must be lit at the southeast corner
若蜡烛熄灭
If the candle goes out
必须将到手的财物原物放回  退出墓穴
the Mojins must return the treasures and leave the tomb.
否则将有灾祸发生
Or else there would be catastrophes.
墓主为防盗设下的致命机关
To escape the deadly traps is no more than a piece of cake...
对他们来说  都不费吹灰之力
for the Mojins.
鸡鸣灯灭不摸金
Candles are dimming out.
撤手
Leave it!
哎哎哎
Wait.
别这样  咱可几个月没开张了
We've been out of business for months!
这煮熟的鸭子  咱不能又让它这么飞了
We can't let this treasure slip!
胡八一
Hu Bayi!
一九八八年  在Shirley杨的强烈要求下
1988, Mojin Xiaoweis retired from tomb raiding
摸金二人组移居美国纽约
and fled to New York in Shirley's demand.
嘿姑娘  过来
Hi girl, come on.
看我看我
Look at me. Look at me.
中国的宝贝
Chinese treasures!
你看看
You see see.
怎么样
What do you think?
我这宝贝儿喜欢吗  可以吧
Do you like my babes?
财宝
Treasures!
文化
Culture!
运气
Luck!
运气  真的吗
Good Luck. Really?
我是谁
Who I am?
他是谁
Who he is?
我们是摸金校尉你知道吗
We are 'Mojin Xiaowei', you know?
功夫你知道吗  功夫
Kung Fu! You know? Kung Fu!
非常棒
Very Great.
如果你功夫那么好
If your Kung Fu's so great
为什么在街头卖东西
why are you doin' business on the street?
他们说美国牛狮
They say America is sick!
老王
Wang
好像有点不对劲啊
Something's wrong here.
稍甭会儿  喷差不多了
One sec, almost there.
给我看一下你的证件
Show me your ID.
什么
What?
我是美国移民局的
This is the INS.
转过身把手放到身后
Turn around. Put your hands behind your back.
对不起我不懂英语
Sorry I...I don't know English...
你叫什么
What is your name?
你从哪里来的
Where are you from?
嘿
Hey!
我们有证件
We have ID.
证件
ID!
证件啊
证件
Ah..ID!
我知道  我知道
I know I know I know...
跑啊
Run!!!
我是杜汉探员  追捕两名亚洲男子
This is Officer Durham. We are chasing two Asian men...
往哪跑啊
Where to?
寻龙分金看缠山  一重缠是一重关
To seek the Dragon through obstacles, each obstacle is a gate
左手百老汇  右手中央大街
Left to Broadway, right to Central Street.
走上不走下  走左不走右
Up instead of down, left instead of right.
少废话
Shut up!
往哪拐呀
Left or right?
往左
Left!
开始我就觉得不对  果然是个女特务
I knew there was something wrong with her.
看着点
Watch out!
这寻龙诀在美国不好使啊
Dragon Seeking doesn't work here.
走
Go!
上车
Get in !
杨参谋
Yang!
你们先走  我断后
You guys go first and I take care of the rest.
还断后
What?
再不走就绝后了
The rest? You'd better take care of yourself.
他们在那
There!
堂堂的个摸金校尉
We are the "Mojin Xiaowei".
天天让人追的跟个孙子似的满街跑
But here we are chased on the streets all the time.
大跌份了
What the fuck!
还不如被遣送回国呢
I'd rather be sent back to China
待这么个破地儿
What the hell is this country.
哪都找不到你
I can't find you anywhere.
躲着我啊
Are you hiding from me?
没有啊
No way.
我躲着你干嘛
Why would I hide from you?
我妈跟我说
Mom told me,
如果你跟一个男人上了床
if you have slept with a man
别主动联系他
never contact him first.
等他联系你
Wait for him to come to you.
我妈还跟我说
My mom also told me,
如果那个男人不主动联络你
If he doesn't
就忘了他
forget about him.
咱阿姨还挺想得开的啊
What a cool mom.
不用躲着我了
You don't need to hide.
就当那天晚上什么也没发生过
Let's just pretend nothing had happened.
没错
Yeah!
我也是跟老胡这么说的
That was that I said.
那天晚上喝多少酒啊
We were so drunk.
我抱着马桶就睡了一宿
I slept with the toilet the whole night.
哎
Ah.
都醉成那样了
Drunk like that,
无论干了什么
You two would have regretted
第二天一定悔的肠子都青了  是不是
Whatever you've done.
他说的是金盆洗手那事儿
He's talking about us quitting.
那不然呢
Of course.
你以为我说什么
What else would I talk about?
二两黄汤下肚
A couple of shots down and we were finished.
还就金盆洗手了
We've been raiding all our lives
倒斗那么多年说不干就不干了
how can we just quit?
那不开玩笑嘛这不是
Are you kidding me?
哎
Well,
这事就这么定了啊
that's already decided.
别在这瞎掰扯
period.
要不咱们结婚吧
How about getting married?
假结婚
I mean fake marriage.
这样你在美国就可以拿到绿卡
Then you could get the green card.
有一个身份  你也可以找到一份正经的工作
And find a proper job...
堂堂的摸金校尉
A Mojin Xiaowei
得靠假结婚才能混口饭吃
has to rely on fake marriage to get a job...
这跟卖身有什么区别
Why not be a hooker?
要祖师爷知道了
If the master had known this,
得从地底下爬出来掐死你们俩
he'd crawl out from the grave to beat you up.
你别再提摸金校尉了
Stop talking about "Mojin Xiaowei."
咱们在祖师爷面前磕过头  拔香散伙了
We've made the vow to quit
这是事实你得认
There's no way around
我、我那喝多了
I...I was drunk...
我断片了、我、我
I...I don't remember anything.
这事我不认
I don't.
你们男人就这么不负责任是吧
You irresponsible men!
哎  那你对祖师爷  你负责任了吗
We gotta be responsible for our profession first.
哎  这摸金符这可是祖师爷给咱留下的
He passed the Mojin Amulet on to us with his expectations.
就这么散伙了
And here we are.
昨天金牙又给咱介绍了一单大的
Grill just got us a big deal.
我说咱就趁这机会重出江湖
Let's get back to the business
省得在这鬼地方受这洋罪
and leave this 'sick America.'
啊
Yo?
你、你干嘛
What are you doing.
没有你胡八一
Hu Bayi!
这地球照样转
The wold won't stop because of you.
你
You
好好看一看
Have a carefully look
这可是我们清朝慈禧太后老佛爷的陪葬
These are the treasures from the tomb of Empress Dowger Cixi.
摸金校尉 冒死从她嘴里边抠出来的这颗夜明珠
Mojin Xiaoweis risked their lives to dig out this pearl out of her mouth.
集天地之精华  可保尸身万年不腐
It absorbed the essence of the nature to preserve her body from decay.
这个珍珠是来自中国最著名女皇帝的墓
This pearl's from Chinese most famous woman's tomb.
非常好
Very good.
您一看就是个行家呀
You are a true expert.
看来一般的宝贝还真入不了您的法眼
A mediocre piece won't get your attention.
秦始皇听说过吧
You surely heard of the Emperor of Qin.
那是我们中国的第一个皇帝
The first emperor of China.
他的墓也是摸金校尉开的
His tomb was also raided by the Mojins.
这就是秦始皇的镇殿之宝
This piece is the greatest among the all.
秦王照骨镜
The Skeleton Mirror.
这镜子来自中国第一个皇帝的墓 非常非常好
"...tomb, very very good.
哎哟喂
Look who's here!
来来来  我给您隆重介绍一下
I would like to proudly present
来的这位爷不是别人呐
this gentleman,
那正是东汉三国魏武帝曹操敕封的
who is none other than the legendary Emperor Weiwu's
摸金校尉第八十二代传人  探墓界的大拿
eighty-second generation of Mojin Xiaowei, the No.one of tombraiders
王凯旋  凯爷
Mr. Wang Kaixuan.
胡爷呢
Where is Mr. Hu?
你大爷的  这孙子
Fuck that bastard!
唉哟
Well...
赶紧过来  赶紧过来
Come and see ! Come come!
来来来来
Come come!
看看
Look, look.
这就是传说中的摸金符
This is the legendary Mojin Amulet,
此乃正宗摸金校尉的标志啊
The signature of a real Mojin Xiaowei.
哎哟  凯爷
Mr. Kai
您、您这是怎么话说的您呐
What's going on?
来来来  快坐  快坐
Come and sit here.
你好
Hello.
我是环球矿业集团法务代表  马克
I'm the Executive director of Global Mining Co, Mark.
洋子小姐是董事长秘书
Miss Yoko is our president's secretary.
我们董事会会长应彩虹女士 对中国古文明很感兴趣
Our president Madam Ying Caihong is very interested in ancient Chinese culture.
她很看重  摸金校尉的专业技术
She rates highly of the skills of Mojin Xiaowei.
吩咐不惜任何代价  都要请
And is expecting your assistance
您  出山
regardless of cost.
不去
No.
那要这么说
If so,
这单活儿  那怎么也得
I'd say that at least
五
five...
十万美刀啊
...hundred thousand dollars.
没问题
No problem.
就这么定了
Let's make it a deal.
这是古墓资料和合约
Here is the information of the tomb and our contract.
合同  我来签
I'll sign the contract.
合、合什么同啊  你签
What contact?
你签  签  签
What the hell are you doing?
兄弟这么多年了
It's been so many years
凯爷  凯爷
Mr. Kai.
摸金校尉  合则生分则死
Mojins as a team; United we stand, divided we fall.
胡八一这孙子已经彻底叛变革命了
Hu Bayi, son of a bitch, has betrayed us!
有了钱  谁叛变咱都不怕了
It doesn't matter if we have money.
就这么定了
So let's do it.
我看这么着吧
Let me suggest something
大家都有诚意
for the sake of your sincerity
再加五万
Another fifty thousand.
多、多少 三万
What? Thirty thousand?
那不可能
No way!
你误会了
You misunderstood.
她的意思是给你加三倍
She means she'll triple your offer.
够你这种人花一辈子了
Far enough for people like you.
签合同吧
Sign the contract then.
得嘞
Oh Yeah.
你大爷的
Fuck off.
你有钱是吧
You got money huh ?
您是付现金这是支票啊
Cash or check?
有钱牛逼啊
You think you are something?
我顶瞧不上你们这帮有钱就装大尾巴狼的
Fuck you people who think money can buy everything.
凯爷
Mr. Kai!
要拿钱砸老子是吧  砸呀
You wanna buy me out with money?
告诉你  没门儿
Let me tell you, no bloody way.
老子叫王凯旋  凯爷
I am Wang Kaixuan, Mr. Kai!
有床不睡睡帐篷
Why are you sleeping in the tent?
有病吧你
Weirdo.
今天  戊辰年丙辰月
According to Fengshui
辛丑土危开日
today
西北  危月燕凶  六曜先负
today is not a good day
辛不合酱  丑不冠带
for trade
忌  交易入仓  相亲结婚
or marriage...
够了够了
Enough!
没有人要跟你结婚
No one wants to marry you.
我本来想睡醒了之后去找你
I was planning to see you after I woke up...
把咱们俩的事给理一理
and discuss about us...
咱们俩的事有什么好理的
What about us?
你的态度都已经说明一切了
Your attitude already made the conclusion.
我允许你后悔
You are allowed to regret.
我没后悔
I don't regret it.
然后呢
So?
嗯
Yeah?
什么然后
So what?
我不是来找你算帐的
I'm not here to argue with you.
你有东西送到我那了
You have something delivered to my place.
啊
Ah.
这是我最后一次帮你取东西了
This is the last time I pick it up for you.
以后我放在门房那  你自己拿
Next time I'll leave it at the door. You go get it.
诶
Hey...
别这样
Take it easy...
你要是一撒手
If you leave us alone
这后勤工作整个儿就乱套了
we'll be in a mess.
走了
Ciao.
哎
Hey!
我跟你说个事啊  我回国了
Just wanna tell you that I'm back to China.
我不是跟你置气  我也没那工夫
Not because of you. I don't have time for the argument.
我去探个辽代古墓
I'm going to check out this tomb from Liao Dynasty.
这事跟钱没关系  本来不想跟你说的
It has nothing to do with money, and I didn't mean to tell you this...
不为钱才怪
Yeah, right.
彼岸花
But the Equinox flower...
这朵花还记得吧
You do remember this flower right?
小丁说的彼岸花又出现了
The special kind of lily mentioned by Ding appears again.
我这次回去是为了小丁
This time I came back tor Ding.
我得把这事儿搞清楚
I need to find out what's going on.
你去不去随便吧
It's up to you to join me or not.
又回去盗墓
Going back to old business again.
还故弄玄虚的搞了盘录像
And now he's trying to drag you into this
明显就是要拉你回去嘛
by sending this inveracious tape.
不会
No.
关于丁思甜的事
Wang would never use Ding Sitian
老王绝不会开玩笑
as the bait.
丁思甜是谁啊
Who's Ding Sitian?
一九六九年  中国  内蒙古
1969, Inner Mongolia, China
二十年前
Twenty years ago,
我和老王响应上山下乡号召
Wang and I relocated ourselves in Inner Mongolia
到内蒙草原插队
for 'Up to the Mountains and Down to the countryside'.
那年夏天
That summer
我们一伙知青让牧民带路
we marched into the forbidden area led
深入禁地
by the herdsmen,
要找传说的千年神女墓  破四旧
searching for the thousand year Goddess tomb, to destroy the 'Four-olds'.
丁思甜是我们的战友
Ding Sitian was our comrade
父母都是知名的植物学家
her parents were both renowned botanists.
她从小能歌善舞  是知青里的文艺骨干
Ding was talented in music and art.
千万颗红心向着北京
Thousands of red hearts facing Beijing
千万张笑脸迎着红太阳
Thousands of smiling faces greeting the red sun
敬祝领袖毛主席万寿无疆
in praise of Long Life for Chairman Mao
敬爱的毛主席
Dear Chairman Mao...
啊
Ah!
怎么回事
What's the matter?
你老实站着啊  不许动
You stay put and don't move!
车轮卡住了
The wheel is stuck!
啊  咋整啊
What should we do?
大家别慌  下来推车  快点
Don't panic! Everybody push, hurry!
小丁  来
Ding, come.
不用  我自己来
It's okay. I can to it.
哎你草原上的花儿还没采齐吧
You haven't finished your flower collection yet right?
你有什么没找到的你跟我说我肯定给你找到
Let me know If you are missing any and I'll find it for you.
哎  这种体力活儿交给老王  老王可厉害了
Leave all the hard work to Wang, he can surely handle it.
可上九天揽月  敢下五洋捉鳖
He can climb up to the moon and dive down to the ocean.
咱俩就在地面上  跳跳舞  弹弹琴
While we sing and dance on the ground.
我陪你
I'll stay with you
哎  哎
Hey Hey!
一个人做点坏事并不难
'It's not difficult to commit some misdeeds.
难的是啊  一辈子只做坏事  不做好事
But it's difficult to commit only misdeeds and no good deeds,' said Chairman Mao.
这说的就是你
He meant exactly you.
有情况
Attention!
什么情况
What happened?
戒备  那有敌人
Be alarmed, enemy ahead!
抄家伙  快走
Get your weapons, hurry!
来来来  拿着
Come and take this!
走
Go!
小丁  你放心啊
Ding,don't worry.
哎  哎
Hey!
去那边看看
Take a look there.
大家看着脚下
Watch out the mud.
哪来的什么敌人  瞎诈呼
They are enemies?
不就是一堆石头像嘛
They're only statues.
那边都是啊
More over there!
这还有
And here!
那边也有
There too!
不能去
Don't get closer.
为什么啊
Why?
高大的石神保佑  伟大的神女保佑
...guarded by the stones... blessed by the Goddess...
他说什么呢
What's he saying?
老人家说  我们已经来到生死的边界
He says that we've arrived to the limbo of life and death.
这石像是守卫冥界的士兵
These are the guards of the Underworld.
我们不能再往前了
We must go no further or else none will return.
这神头鬼脸的事你熟  什么路子
You know this shit.
这什么情况  你说话啊
What's going on here?
这地界儿  是有点邪性
This area is indeed strange.
历代劳动人民群众闹革命
Throughout the history we working class people
都要先挖帝王皇陵
would always break the emperors' tombs for revolutions!
对
True!
说的对
Indeed!
这是表现和封建反动势力干到底的决心
It shows the determinations against the feudal power!
哎  等等  等等
Hold on, hold on!
等等
Hold on!
伟大领袖毛主席说过
The Great Chairman Mao said
要团结一切可团结的力量  是不是
All power can be united must be united, right?
是
Right!
看
Look!
这些士兵  搁古代他们也是无产阶级
These soldiers were the proletarians of the old days!
咱们
Shouldn't we
把它团结团结不就行了嘛
unite them too?
有道理
You got a point.
你放屁
Bullshit.
反动的东西你不打  他就不倒
All counter-reactionaries must be abolished.
不好意思  打扰各位了  不好意思啊
Excuse us to disturb you...Excuse us...
唯有牺牲多壮志  敢叫日月换新天
Only the greatest ambitions and sacrifice lead to a brave new world!
换新天
A brave new world!
咱们把这些石像砸了
Let's destroy the statues!
砸了
Destroy them!
使劲拉
Harder!
排除万难  争取胜利
Through all hardship victory will be ours!
同志们  这是人民群众的伟大胜利
Comrades, this is a great victory of the people!
伟大胜利
Great victory!
接下来  让我们去捣毁神女墓
Now let's go and destroy the tomb of the Goddess!
他们都疯了吧
They've gone mad
怎么了
What's the matter?
有情况
Something's wrong.
等等
Hold on.
有情况
Attention.
大家小心
Watch out everybody!
地下有动静
Something's moving underground.
你这个封建迷信反革命  马上给我闭嘴
Shut up you superstitious counterrevolutionary two-faces.
我去
Oh my god...
拉小丁跑
Get Ding out of there!
往这边跑  往这边跑
Run! This way!
跑  跑啊
Run! Run!
别跑散了  这边
This way!
跑啊
Run!
你们都是纸老虎
You are all the paper tigers!
快  快啊
Hurry up!
趴下
Get down!
走
Go!
快
Quickly!
跟上
Hurry up!
小丁
Ding!
老王
Wang!
老胡  这儿  这儿
Hu, come here!
走
Go!
快过来  快过来
Come here quickly!
这儿
Here!
快进来
Inside!
衣服
Cover it!
那么多战友  都牺牲了
We've lost so many comrades.
怎么办  那我们出不去了
What do we do now?
没事的  别害怕
It's okay.
会有办法  会有办法的
There's always something.
大家别慌
Stay calm.
大家不要慌  别慌
老王  老王
Wang! Wang!
这边有门
Here's a door.
这是哪啊
Where is this place?
小心点
Be careful.
跟紧点
Follow up!
这什么鬼地方啊
What the hell is this place?
这么深呐
It's so deep.
大家小心脚底
Watch out the steps.
这还能出去吗
Is this the way out?
没事的
It's okay...
这是哪啊
Where is this place?
咱们这到什么地方了  这么大
It's huge here...
大家四处看看
Look around
找条路出去
Find a way out.
别怕  跟着我
Follow me. Don't be afraid.
嗯
Okay.
哎  这没路了
Here's a dead end.
老王
Wang.
看来我们进了日本鬼子的地下工事了
It looks like a Japanese underground military base.
啊
Ah?
地下工事
Military base?
就是日本兵挖的地道
Tunnel for war.
往这边走  你打头阵  我垫后
There. You lead the way, I bring up the rear.
配电室
Power distribution room.
弹药库
Ammunition depot.
你跟老胡断后
You follow Hu.
地、地下工事
Un...underground base...
这不会还有日本鬼子吧  啊
Hope there's no Japanese here...
哎行了  有也早死了
Come on. They are all dead.
别自己吓唬自己
Don't scare yourself.
哎  不是  这
I mean...
炸药包
Dynamite!
哎  这好像是个升降机啊
This looks like a dumbwaiter.
升降机
A dumbwaiter!
那从这可以出去啊
We can get out from here!
真的  太好了
Yeah!!
这都多少年了  还能用吗
Is't still working?
这什么东西啊
What's this?
这还有个弹药库啊
Here's another ammunition depot.
灭了  灭了
Put it out!
大家注意啊
Everybody watch out.
每个结构点上都埋了炸药
There are dynamite attached to all the structural joints
一旦点燃  整个工事会坍塌
Once lit up, the entire base will collapse.
灭  留一个照路
Let's just leave one torch for the road.
快灭了  赶紧灭了
Hurry up! Put it out!
我说  先想想办法怎么启动这个升降机啊
We'd better think about how to re-start the dumbwaiter.
你们看  这有电线
Look, here are the wires!
我们沿着电线就能找到发电机
They would lead us to the power generator.
走  咱们过去看看
Let's have a look.
来  使劲啊
Come on!
成了
It's on!
我们可以出去了
Yes!
太好了
Great!
亮了亮了
It's on!
我们可以出去了
We can get out!
我们走吧
Let's go.
别怕  别怕
Don't be afraid.
没事  没事
It's okay. It's okay.
你看
You see,
他已经死了  是干尸
A dried corpse.
别害怕
It's okay.
大爷的  死这么多人啊
God... It's full of corpses.
这些日本兵怎么都死在这了
How come these Japanese died here?
你看  他们还有枪呢
Look they all carry guns.
喂  那边有石像
Statues over there!
我们还是回去吧
We should go back.
对啊  那边危险  我们还是回去吧
Yeah it's dangerous there. We'd better go back.
回去吧
Let's go back.
叫我说咱别找那麻烦了  咱出去就安全了
Let's not get ourselves in trouble.
走走走
Let's go.
走吧
Yeah, let's go.
怕什么
What are you all afraid of?
我们是唯物主义者
We are materialists.
彻底的唯物主义者  是无所畏惧的
True materialists are fearless.
大家把红宝书都掏出来
Take out your little red book.
快点
Quickly!
都掏出来
Take it out!
彻底的唯物主义者  是无所畏惧的
True materialists are fearless.
前面就是四旧  把它砸了
Let's smash the "Four olds."
这些鬼子死的很奇怪
These Japanese all dead in strange ways.
应该是挖到这些石像
It seems that they found these statues
想要运走
and tried to move them away.
却突然发生了什么
Then Something happened.
这些四旧怎么说
Whatever these 'F our-ems' are,
那也是老粽子留给我们无产阶级的
They are for us proletarians.
怎么算也轮不着这些小鬼子啊
Not for the Japanese invaders!
拿着
Take it.
防身
For self defense!
好
Okay.
没事  我罩着你
Don't worry, I'm protecting you.
谢谢
Thank you.
走
Let's go.
彼岸花
The Equinox flower!
什么
What?
这就是彼岸花  传说只开在阴阳交界
According to the legend, it only exists at the limbo of Yin and Yang,
有接引亡灵和联通生死的神奇功能
and connect the living and the dead.
彼岸花
The Equinox flower?
据说它花开的时候特别美
Yes, I heard the flower's so beautiful.
是吗
Yeah?
我好想亲眼看一下
I really want to see it.
你这事  这事交我身上
Count it on me!
真的
Really?
就是它开在阴曹地府
I'll find it for you
我也一定给你采回来
even it's in hell.
那一言为定
You promise.
听我说  里面
There are still many 'Four-olds'
还有好多四旧呢
to be destroyed.
同志们往里冲啊
Comrades, let's go!
往里冲啊
Go!
那边危险
It's dangerous!
等等
Hold on!
这地底下还有这么大空间啊
It's huge.
大爷的
God damn it!
这么多石像得砸到什么时候啊
It'll take us forever to destroy them all.
同志们  把它们都给我砸了
Comrades, let's do it!
不要砸
Don't!
别砸
Stop it!
怎么回事
What's wrong?
有鬼子
The Japanese!
这活见鬼了
What the hell is that?
救我
Help!
快下来
Come down!
走啊
Go!
小心
Careful!
走
Go
小丁
Ding!
滚开
Get out!
我去你的
Fuck off!
胡八一
Hu Bayi!
放开我
Let me go.
小丁
Ding!
老王
Wang!
凯旋  快走
Wang Hurry up!
走
Go!
我去你的
Damn it!
快跑
Run!
炸弹被引爆
It exploded.
地下基地变成一片火海
The place was turned into a sea of fire.
我们不顾一切地往外跑
We ran for our lives,
丁思甜和所有战友都在爆炸中牺牲
Ding Sitian and our comrades all died...
只有我和老王
Only Wang and myself
乘坐升降机逃出了基地
managed to escape by the dumbwaiter.
二十年了
It's been twenty years.
老王一直不愿提起这件事情
Wang never wanted to bring this up.
当时我们看到的彼岸花
At that time we saw the Equinox flower.
据说是一千多年前契丹公主奥古的标志
I've heard that it's the sign of Princess Augo from Khitan.
没想到
I never expect that
它竟然又出现了
it would appear again.
但你说你看到的日军干尸  竟然复活了
You said that you witnessed the corpses coming back to life
还跟你们厮杀
to kill you...
这不科学
It's impossible.
事后想起来
In hindsight
确实不合理
it was indeed impossible.
只是那个场景
It's just that moment
真的是大真实了
was too real to me.
会不会你们看到的  都不是真的呀
Perhaps it was just an illusion.
但是我的战友是真牺牲了
But my comrades did die,
我跟老王  也差一点儿没出来
and nearly did Wang and I.
有没有可能
Maybe it was because of the
因为地底下缺氧
lack of oxygen
或者你们吸入了一些有毒的气体
or that you breathed in some toxic gas
导致你们看到了一些无法解释的现象
that you saw some unexplainable phenomena?
你也知道人们看到的东西
You know that seeing is not believing.
不是眼睛决定的
What you believe to be true is not determined by your eyes
是脑子决定的
but your brain.
我明白你的意思
I know what you mean.
我认为你漂亮
I think that you are pretty
并不是客观上  你漂亮
doesn't mean you are physically pretty
而是我心里认定你漂亮
but my brain believed that you're pretty...
是吧
Right?
想干嘛
What do you want.
老王一个人回去我不放心
I can't leave Wang alone.
你已经金盆洗手了
You've already quit.
你别误会啊
Don't take me wrong.
我不是想重操旧业
I'm not gonna go back to the 'business'.
我只是想把老王给拽回来
I just wanna get Wang back.
一个人
By yourself?
啊
Yeah.
我又不是回去探墓
I'm not gonna rob the tomb anyway.
一个人没问题
I can do it myself.
我找到老王就回来
I'll be back once I find him.
你放心  啊
Don't you worry.
你回不回来跟我一点关系都没有
It doesn't matter if you come back or not.
我才不在乎呢
I don't give a shit!
Shirley
Shirley!
胡八一你这个大骗子
You fucking liar Hu Bayi!!
我已经看透你了
I knew you!
说一套做一套
What you've said has nothing to do with what you've done!
我绝对不会再相信你这个
I'll never trust you anymore!
自私自利又自以为是的自大狂
You fucking arrogant egoistic asshole!
你跟王凯旋加在一起就是个麻烦
You and Wang Kaixuan together are nothing but troubles.
我倒要亲眼看看
Show me
你们两个到底还能闯多大的祸
How much trouble you can make!
雄关漫道真如铁
The long journey I've been through is still there
而今迈步从头越
And now I am coming back to the start.
我王凯旋又回来啦
Wang Kaixuan is back!
这都溜溜儿的走了一整天了
We've been on the horse the whole day,
真把哥儿们给累龇了
Man I'm exhausted.
要不是冲着美金的面儿
I'm never gonna come to this god damn shit hole
谁他妈来这鬼地方啊
if not for the dollars.
我说你嘴巴放干净点儿啊
Watch your mouth.
当年我就是跟老胡在这儿插的队
Hu and I spent our youth here.
这可你自个儿提的胡爷啊
Well you brought him,
我可没蹿蹬你
I didn't.
呸  提他我就来气
Screw him
这个没出息的个东西
Such a loser who
经不住糖衣炮弹的诱惑
'can't withstand the sugar-coated bullets.'
三下两下就让美帝女特务给策反了
Subverted by the female agent of the American Imperialism in a blink.
现在世道不一样啦  妇女能顶半边天呐
This world has changed now - 'women hold up half the sky.'
您瞅瞅那小妹妹  样儿大了去了
or more than half! Look at that chick!
好好一草原让你们给折腾成这幅德行
Is this a mining company or a tomb developing company?
你们也太明目张胆了
This is sick.
这方圆二百里都被我们集团租下了
We have rented 200 square miles of this land
随时可以地质勘探
for geological prospecting.
就等摸金校尉出手啦
It's all yours.
这位
This
就是我们的董事会会长  应彩虹女士
is our President Ms. Ying Caihong.
这姐姐就会长啊
That's the president?
一办气功班儿的呀
Some sort Yoga class?
瞧瞧人家这企业文化
What a company!
摸金校尉请来了
Mojin Xiaowei is here.
真有范儿啊
Cool, isn't it!
又不对
Wrong again.
还是岩层
It's rock.
这刚刚跟着感觉走
I got too excited
一不小心大发了
following my instinct.
咱们这明明要找神女墓
We were looking for the Goddess Tomb.
这一兴奋找成龙穴了
But we got the dragon tomb haha.
这都第九个坑了  你到底行是不行啊
This is the ninth hole, are you doing this right?
那要怪就怪胡八一这混帐玩意儿
You should blame Hu Bayi.
这分金定穴一向是他的事儿
Locating has always been his thing.
他要在的话  咱们现在早在墓穴里面了
We would have already found it if he's here.
行了行了  别说那没用的了啦
It's no use to complain now.
再找不到咱俩可就得成大粽子啦
They are gonna blow us instead if we can't find it.
别让他们再浪费我的时间了
Ask them not to waste my time.
你大爷的
Fuck.
炸了好几天  连个墓道影子都没看到
It's been ages and we still got nothing.
老实说  你  这摸金校尉是骗子吧
This 'Mojin Xiaowei' is a faker, isn't he.
哎哟  我的亲妹妹
Hey,young lady
你可冤死我啦
trust me.
这分金定穴啊
'Fen Jin Ding Xue' takes time.
是个技术活儿  那可得花点儿工夫啊
It's a serious job.
所谓分金呐
Fen jin' means to locate
就是用罗盘定位
using ancient compass.
这罗盘一周呢  是三百六十度
The compass divides into 360 degrees,
又分成了二十四山
24 zones.
每山呢又细分五金
Each zone breaks further into five golds,
一共是一百二十金那
making a total of 120 golds.
统筹这东南西北四面八方
We take all the geological positions
所有的地理位置
into account...
听不懂  说人话
Speak Chinese.
我这么跟你说吧  用现在流行的电脑语言
Speak it in technology terms
这分金就是数据
If 'Fen jin' is the data,
寻龙诀就是运算程式
'Dragon Seeking' would be the programme.
输入资料进行推演  那就是定穴
The way the programme works with the data is 'ding xue'.
这方圆数百里的龙穴卖地
Once it's done,
那是一览无余
all the tombs in this area will be found.
你听明白了吗
Do you know what I mean?
妹妹  哎
Ouch!
妹妹你什么意思啊
What do you want young lady?
金牙  给我看你的漂亮牙
Show me your gills.
干嘛呢
Yo!
干嘛昵  放开我兄弟
Leave him alone!
从现在开始
From now on,
每炸错一个坑我就拔他一颗牙
I will pull one tooth out every time you get it wrong
直到找到墓穴为止
till you find get it right.
如果天黑前还找不到
If there's nothing found by dawn,
我就执行违约条款
I shall execute the breaching of terms.
什么违约条款啊
What breaching of terms?
一人一个坑  自己跳
One hole for each of you.
老金  咱合同里边有这条吗
Grill, is that true?
签的什么操蛋合同
What kind of damn contract is that?
合作愉快
Cheers.
别急别急  别急啊
Calm down,
不就找个墓门嘛
It's just a fuckin tomb...
小丁啊
Ding...
有了有了
That's it!
开那儿肯定有戏
There! Must be something!
浓浓烈烈的奶酒啊
Drunkard's song in Mongolian
蜷在瓶里的小绵羊
其实吧  你在大后方坐镇挺好的
It's nice for you to be here.
这趟我们仨不能都陷进来
But this time we can't afford to have all of us trapped here.
否则  不又回到老路子上面去了
Or else it's gonna be the same all over again.
摸金校尉合则生  分则死
Mojin Xiaowei, United we stand, divided we fall.
这是祖师爷的遗训  我必须得来
It's what the master told us. I must come.
而且  这一伙人不是一般倒斗的
These people are not regular graverobbers.
我查了一下这帮所谓的环球矿业集团
I've checked upon this Global Mining Group.
这不像一般的企业  倒像是开法会的
It's more of a cult than a company.
而他们要找的  就是你说的那个奥古公主墓
The tomb of Princess Aogu you mentioned before is exactly what they are looking for.
有点意思
Interesting.
这位公主有双重身份  她既是皇族
She has double identities:
又是萨满祭司
a royal blood and shaman,
被人奉之为神女
worshipped as a Goddess,
彼岸花是她的法宝
The Equinox flower is her instrument.
据说呢  能打开生死之门
Legends tell the flower opens the gate
穿越阴阳两界
to the underworld.
让人死而复生
It brings the dead back to life.
这司机是不是喝太多了
This guy is too drunk to drive.
别担心
Don't worry.
当地人酒量好
The locals are all like this
喝得越多开得越稳
the more they drink the better they drive.
我再喝一点儿  我的车就飞起来啦
A little bit more, I can take you both high up to the sky.
没事吧
Are you okay?
你开车
You drive the car.
大哥  我来开吧
Hey bro, let me drive.
不用  你可坐好了啊
Just sit back and relax.
你的屁股还没坐热呢
We are almost there.
我就到了
Almost!
踩刹车
Take the Break!
不管用啦  失灵啦
It's not working!
打轮
Make a turn!
马群  马群  要撞马群啦
Oh my god we are gonna hit the horses.
松手
Let go!
你放手啊
Let it go!
完蛋了
Oh shit...
胡八一
Hu Bayi!
对不起
Forgive me.
南无阿弥陀佛  南无阿弥陀佛 上帝保佑  上帝保佑
Buddha, God, Save me!
下面很深  空间很大
It's deep down here,
像是个墓道
looks like a it's leading to the tomb
看见没
You see see,
你们谁再敢说我们凯爷是冒牌货
Who's the faker hum?!
凯爷  炸出来了
Mr. Wang, we got it!
摸金校尉名不虚传 虽然把草原炸成了麻子脸
Very impressive. Though you've blown
终于把穴定出来了
this prairie into the surface of the moon.
这是一技术活儿  当然得花工夫啦
Serious business takes time.
哎哎哎  嘛呢
Take it easy.
跟他说  他明白的了吗
It's no use educating the ignorant.
那我也得让他知道啊
But the ignorant needs to be educated!
喝酒还开什么车啊
You shouldn't drink and drive...
阿吉吉日嘎拉
(Mongolian)
幸亏没出什么大事
Thank god there's nothing serious.
到了目的地
After you get there,
把马笼头拿下来栓在马鞍子上  放它走
take off the bridle and put it on the saddle.
马自己能回来吗
Can the horse find its way back?
当然  我的马能找到自己家
Of course.
谢谢
Thank you.
祝一路平安
Cheers,
牧民大哥说了  只能借我们一匹马
The Herdsman only has one horse for us
你就留在这儿等我  我找到老王就回来接你
You stay here. I'll come back after I find Wang.
你是想甩下我吧
You do wanna get rid of me huh.
你留在这里安全
You'll be safe here.
胡八一你去死
Go to hell. Hu Bayi!
阿爸的马群里
(Mongolian nursery rhyme) My favorite pony
有我最喜爱的小马驹
hides in daddy's horses...
喜欢吗
Do you like it?
Shirley
左边那绳子往里拽
Drag the left rope inwards.
右边看着点儿
Watch out.
让  让  让
Get out of the way
忙着呢
I'm busy
嘛呢
What are you doing ?
瞧见没有这阵势
Do you see this?
我说  咱这倒斗的这套家伙事儿
Don't you think that
是不是有点大跌份了
our gears are a bit out of time.
我说您也别老跟着感觉走啊
Don't just follow your instinct.
咱也得跟上点时代的步伐不是嘛
We should also follow our times.
咱走着瞧
We'll see
这都是咱祖师爷那会儿传下来的玩意
There tools are inherited from a thousand years ago,
就这身家伙事儿  已经检验一千多年了
and have been examined more than a thousand years.
你懂个屁啊你
What the hell do you know?
空气安全  抓紧准备
The air is safe, get prepared.
真没劲
Boring
什么都用电动的  这叫倒斗吗这叫
Every thing's electronic. What's the fun of it?!
两边抓紧时间  再检查一下
Hurry up guys!
好嘞
Okay
老金  别愣着  跟着我
What are you doing, Grill? Follow me
你先下去  你先下去
You get down there first
这么大领导  亲自下呀
Ladies, do think twice.
可别怪我没提醒你啊 这倒斗可不是请客吃饭
Raiding a tomb is no joke
就您这身子板儿
Look at you,
经得起折腾吗
are you ready for this?
人活着  总是需要一点精神
We all live by beliefs.
我说
How about
要不  我送各位到这吧
I leave you ladies and gentlemen here.
我是经纪人  耍嘴皮子的
I'm just a business man you know,
这倒斗它不是我专业
Tomb raiding is not my thing.
我就不下去给大伙儿添乱了
I'd better stay here.
一  二
One two
三
three
瞎抡什么呢
What are you doing?
这是千年颜料遇到空气的挥发现象
This is what happens when the ancient paints react to the air.
这丢人现眼的
Get educated, ignorant!
您瞧瞧
You see?
See?
这就是专业和业余的区别
This is the difference between professional and amateur.
哎对了  还有看好你的人
By the way, keep an eye on your guys.
从现在开始
From now on
一切听我的最高指示
everybody follows my order.
这是契丹文吧
Is this Khitanan?
这写的什么啊这是
What does it say?
用屁股想也知道  这上面写的是
A blind would see that it says
盗墓者死
Tomb raiders shall die.
这不只四个字啊这
It is more than a few words
哎呦哟哟  这壁画  一千多年了  这品相
This frescoe must have been for a thousand years.
这要是弄一块带回美国 这起码能换艘大游艇啊
We can get at least a cruise if we trade it in the US.
到时候咱再找几个美国小妹妹
And some girls too.
我这一脚也算没白挨啊我
Worth getting some kicks.
唉  等等我  等等我
Wait for me!
你们去那边
You guys over there.
唉哟  瞧这位爷
Wow, look at him.
真有范儿啊
Great pose.
不是你瞧你
Enough...
这就一看大门的
This is just a door man.
你看那神像是长了个狗头吗
Is that a dog head?
我说你们几个别乱动啊
Don't mess around.
都听凯爷的  都听凯爷的啊
Follow his order.
尊师  这和我们之前得到的铜徽是一样的
Master, this bronze badge is the same with what we had.
不  不
No no
这不是小女孩该干的活
This is not a job for little girls
尊师
Master
哎哟喂  这是
Holy shit, this is...
别乱动啊
Keep your hands off
安静
Be quiet.
这干尸晾了上千年
This corpse has been here for more than a thousand years
风一吹自然会变成灰
It goes into dust once the wind blows
别动
Stay still.
这灰有毒
It's poisonous.
别碰他们  会传染
Stay away from them. It's infectious.
尊师
Master
救我
Help Me!
尊师  救我啊  尊师
Master, help me please!
即刻开悟  众生解脱
Let the great awareness descent upon them, and the great relief be with them.
洋子
Yoko, and the great relief be with them.
这帮孙子
Bastards.
怎么啦
What's wrong?
嘛呢
Hey!
你们是耳朵聋了  还是听不懂人话呀
Are you guys deaf?
动哪啦
What did you do?
今夜是我们最后的机会
Tonight is our last chance.
让我们来一起完成解救众生的宏愿
Let's make our aspiration to relieve all creatures come true.
对自己人部下狠手啊
You are so cruel.
即刻开悟  众生解脱
Let the great awareness descent upon them,
我说你们别念妖咒了
and the great relief be with them.
闭嘴嘴  尊师在超度亡灵
Shut up! The Master is releasing the souls of the dead from hell. Keep those nonsense to yourself.
有话好好说啊呀
Take it easy.
小丫头片子
You little pussy.
他还没死
He is still alive
真的没死
For real.
老金  快跑
Grill!Run!
别让他们碰着
Stay away from them.
往哪跑啊
Where to?
一重缠是  一重缠是
The first obstacle is, the first...
去他大爷的  随便
...whatever.
等等我
Wait for me!
怎么回事  怎么回到这啦
We are back here again.
这是什么迷魂洞啊这是
This is a maze.
这是中了什么毒
What poison it is?
这么会儿功夫  活人都变大粽子了
It turned them into zombies.
此路不通换边走
To the other side!
怎么又是这儿啊
Here again.
急急如律令
Abracadabra.
噎死你个大粽子
There you go.
哎
Oi.
你不牛逼吗
You think that you are something?
你啊啊啊  啊你妈呀
Fuck you.
恶心死我了
Gross!
凯爷  这就是传说中
Mr. Wang, this must be the legendary weapon
辟邪驱魔的法宝  大粽子的克星
to kill all the zombies.
黑驴蹄子吧
Hard boiled mule foot.
凯爷  顶住啊
Mr. Wang. hold it off!
我靠  这么邪性啊
Damn...
您这蹄子是过期食品吧
Master Kai, this mule foot might be boiled too much.
天王盖地虎
The heavenly god overpowers the tiger on the ground
宝塔镇河妖
The holy tower suffocates the ghost of the river.
你还真来了
Finally.
走
Go!
太好了
Great.
这下咱可有救啦
Now we are saved.
谁用他救
Who needs to be saved by him?
放着资本主义清福不享
Why don't you go back to the capitalists
你干嘛来了
and drink Coca Cola.
看  人家根本就不需要你
See? They don't need you at all,
就你傻  千里迢迢赶来挨骂
and you are dumb enough to go all the way here only to be scolded.
别斗嘴
Let's get out first
先出去再说
then you can bicker
从原路往回撤
Let's go back from our way in.
走啊
Go!
走
完了  完了  完了  完了
It's over.
这下可绝户了
We're stuck here.
这么多洞口
Surely one of the cave leads to the exit
总有一个是可以离开这儿吧
among all.
每个洞里都有个雕像
There is a statue in each cave.
羊
Goat
鸡
Chicken
狗
Dog
鼠
Mouse
十二生肖
It's the Zodiac.
不对
No.
少了四个  只有八个洞口
Only eight caves.
不是十二生肖
Not twelve.
是八卦
It's the eight trigrams of fortune, the 'Ba Gua'.
到底是什么啊
What on earth is this place?
这几个洞我们来回来去跑了好几趟了
We've been running back and forth for a hundred times.
每个动物都代表一个卦象
Every animal represents a diagram.
寻龙分金看缠山  一重缠是一重关
To seek the Dragon through obstacles, each obstacle is a gate.
关门如有八重睑
All the obstacles
不出阴阳八卦形
are made up of the Ba Gua.
入口为马  马为离卦
The entry is horse. Horse signifies fire.
子鼠遇马为坎离
Mouse,horse, water
未羊遇马为坤离
fire..goat, earth...dog..
戌狗遇马为干离  上干下离见生门
The opposite of northwest is the exit.
戌狗是出口  走
Dog is the exit. Come on!
戌狗
Dog!
去你的  去你的
Go to hell!
走啊
Come on !
走
Let's go!
快啊
Be quick!
不行了  不行了  跑不动了
I can't go on.
你们俩跟我回去  别趟这趟浑水
Let's go back and leave this chaos.
走走走
Go. Let's go.
走
Go.
回  回  回哪儿去
Back. Back where?
我都签了合同了
I've signed the contract.
你就是见钱眼看
You are just a money-grabber,
受不了诱惑
with no resistance to temptation.
受不住诱惑
He is the one
受不住诱惑的是他
with no resistance to temptation.
被你三言两语忽悠到美国去  摆地摊混日子
Fled to America in your trickery, and lived a life by cheating on street.
还好意思闹什么金盆洗手
That's what you call quitting.
看来摸金校尉都到齐了
Now that Mojin Xiaoweis are all here,
这一定是上天的安排
as if instructed by god,
那就都来助我一臂主力吧
you are welcomed to give me your hands.
哎  您等等  您等等
Hold on there,
姐姐
young ladies.
这事啊咱得再论一道了
Now we've got another case.
这二位我想必您早有耳闻
I believe you've heard of these two
大名鼎鼎  胡八一胡爷
The great Mr. Hu, Hu Bayi
Shirley杨小姐
and Miss Shirley Young.
他们都是行内顶尖的高手啊
They are the best of the best.
像凯爷一个人出马
It's one thing to pay
那费用是一回事儿
for Mr. Wang's effort
但是像这种摸金三人合体
and it's another to pay for the Mojin team,
那在业内也是相当罕见
which is rare in our business.
您这福份儿可大了去了
Lucky you.
哎呀  不过
Although,
这费用它也得翻几翻儿呀
the cost will go all the way up.
世人做恶太多
There is too much evil in this world,
人类的劫难即将来临
and great calamities will descend upon human.
只要你们能够助我成事  众生就可以得救
If you can help me, the world will be saved.
刚刚那么多人因为你而死 这也叫众生得救吗
There were so many killed by you. ls that what you call saving the world?
他们是为了更高的信念而死
Their sacrifices are for the greater believes.
是为了你们
For you.
为了我们所有的人
For us all.
他们是伟大的觉悟音
They are the true believers.
你没事吧你
Are you mad?
这位大姐
Madam
实在不好意思
Please excuse us.
我们仨
We three
已经金盆洗手了
have washed our hands,
所以这活儿我们接不了
and this is not our thing any more.
你们也好自为主
You'd better think twice before you act.
走
Let's go.
胡爷  胡爷
Mr Hu,
你们到底要多少钱
How much do you want?
开个价
Name a price.
别装模作样
Stop acting like Saints.
不就一伙儿盗墓贼吗
Petty tomb-raiders.
什么玩意
Say it again?
盗墓贼
Tomb-raiders?
盗墓贼也高你们一等
You are worse than tomb-raiders.
我们这是对封建统治阶级的无情鞭挞
We are 'bringing the feudalism down to the ground'
你们呢
and you?
对自己人都下黑手  你们是什么玩意儿
You are stabbing your people behind their backs. How glorious you are!
这位是无上尊师应彩虹
This is Lady Ying Caihong
出生在中国四川农村
who's born in the countryside of Sichuan Province.
哟  冒牌华侨啊
A faker huh?
据说天生眼珠一黑一黄
She's said to have a black pupil and a yellow one
能见鬼见神
so that she could see the gods and the ghosts.
却被村里的人视为不祥
Deemed to be an ominous figure by the villagers,
后来被一日本富商带到了东京收养
she was adopted by a tycoon from Japan.
两个人关系暧昧  更像
However, it was more than just 'adopted'...
你在胡说  我就不客气了
Stop making stories or I'll make you stop!
杨小姐
Miss Yang.
富商死了之后你便不见了踪影
You were said to be in hospital with illness
传闻是重病住院了是吧
once he passed away.
几年之后你突然出现
Suddenly reappeared several years later,
自称在喜马拉雅山修炼得道  能够解救众生
you claimed to have obtained the power to save the world, after discipline yourself in Everest.
回到香港成立了环球修灵会
Having gone back to Hong Kong, you created the so called "Global Holy Disciplinary institution",
专收这些名门富豪作为弟子
whose members are the ones with fame and fortune
费用昂贵
who would pay quite an amount of money.
Shirley  Shirley  你说这些干什么  真是
Please, Shirley.
姐姐
Dear lady,
哦不
Oh no.
应老板
Boss Ying.
您千万别往心里去啊
Please don't take her words seriously.
咱们这位妹妹她就喜欢刨根问底
Young lady likes to know everything
不过她对您绝对是没有恶意的
but with her heart of kindness...
您看  咱们现在合作刚刚开始是不是
We've just got our collaboration going,
大家不要伤了和气  不要伤了和气
Take it easy.
凯旋
Wang.
干嘛呢
What the hell!
天亮前找到神女棺椁
You find the tomb of the Goddess before dawn,
这位朋友任何伤痛我都能让他复原
and I'll make him fit as a fiddle.
会长
President,
前面有桥
there is a bridge
你小心点我脑袋  啊
Watch out.
你们俩别闹了
Grow up guys.
赶紧找路  尽快脱身
Find a way and get out.
没错没错  再不走我这小命儿就没了
Yes, or I'll say bye bye to the world.
我本来就是一病人  我招谁惹谁了我
What on earth did I do to deserve this.
行了  毛主席他老人家说的对
Chairman Mao said,
要团结不要分裂
Be united, not divided.
我说你这放什么东西了  硌死我了
What's in here? It's so hard.
你看着我干嘛  我还不够团结呀
What are looking at? A person of unity?
团结  团结
Be united, bosses.
各位爷都要团结  逃命要紧呐
Or else we would all die.
那就让他们见识见识
Then we shall let them know
摸金校尉的手段
who Mojin Xiaoweis really are.
你大爷的  我就知道你不能把这摸金符扔了
You asshole, I knew you'd keep the Mojin amulet.
绑在脚脖子上  那能算金盆洗手吗
You said you have washed your hands.
就算这手洗了  这脚还没洗呢
You are the one who cheated!
上次扔的手表  做做样子
I threw my watch instead
好让你死心
to make you give up
那是我送你的表
It was the watch I gave you.
对啊
Yeah
踢得好
Nice kick, buddy
你
You...
我来
Let me do it.
跟着我
Follow me.
凯爷  慢  慢点啊
Watch out, Mr. Wang.
小心
Careful.
过来
Come here.
我去  唉  你这孙子  你怎么越来越沉啊你
You jerk, how come you are getting heavier?
看着跟个猴子似的  你几天没拉屎了吧你
Do you ever poop?
我都这样了  你就别再拿话挤兑我了
Have some pity, sir.
要不是为了大家伙儿  我至于么我
I'm injured only because I worked too hard for you.
先别上去
Don't.
救我
Help.
Help!
这什么桥
What bridge is this?
不会是奈何桥吧这
Bridge to the hell, as it seems.
那个手镯是我送给你的
It is the bracelet I gave to you.
你不是也丢了我送你的表吗
It was the watch I gave to you.
桥面一摩擦就会起火
The bridge sets fire to whatever rubs its surface.
这是一种磷石  燃点极低
It's a material of phosphorus, with very low ignition point.
墓主用磷石造了这些桥
The owner of this tomb built the bridge
就是要让闯入者引火自焚
so that whoever intrudes would be burned to death.
你确定还要继续走吗
Are you sure with your decision?
任何困难都是上天对我们的考验
All obstacles are the tests of God,
我们早已放下了生死
and we are ready to sacrifice ourselves.
摸金校尉  抓紧时间过关吧
Please don't waste your time, Mojin Xiaowei,
你看  我们刚刚经过的这座桥面上
What does the cracking planks
断裂的木板像什么
on the bridge look like?
断
Split
不断  断
not split. Split.
八卦
The eight trigrams .. Ba Gua!
桥面是按照八卦排列的
The planks are in the shape of Ba Gua
过桥的密码就在这些卦象里
In which hides the password.
寻龙分金看缠山  一重缠是一重关
To seek the Dragon through obstacles, each obstacle is a gate.
关门如有八重险  不出阴阳八卦形
All the obstacles are made up of the Ba Gua
坎离震兑分四象  乾坤艮巽含八方
with Eight directions leading to life and death and
八方有生有死门  山泽通气风雷搏
four phases transforming from nature to the universe:
干  震  离  艮
Heaven, Thunder, Fire, Mountain
兑  巽  坤  坎
Lake, Wind, Earth, Water.
西北  东  南  东北
NW, E, S, NE
西  东南  西南  北
W, SE, SW, N
八卦代表的是方向
Ba Gua represents the directions.
走西北  请
North west it is.
你们先走
Please.
哎  我说  咱们要不要再扔个东西试试啊
We don't need to throw something ahead first?
走这边
This way.
快走
Quick.
哟  这位爷也不是善茬儿  赶紧走
This gentleman looks scary. Let's go.
往哪走啊
Which way?
往西南
South West.
洋子
Yoko.
这是最后一枚铜徽  放心去吧
Go to get the last badge.
给我
Give it to me.
尊师  请小心
Be careful Master.
这帮孙子  又动哪了
Dickheads, getting into troubles again !
完了完了  这回要变烤乳猪了
Now we are turning into fillet steaks.
快跑
Run!
快快快
Quick!
快点走
快啊
Quick!
快点啊!
火  火  火烧过来了
The fire is breathing down my neck!
快点往前跑
Move! Quickly!
火上来了  火上来了
It's coming!
凯爷你快  快跑啊
Be quick, Mr.Wang.
快
Quick!
你怎么越来越沉了呀  你
You are gaining weight all the time!
你别说了  快跑啊
Not the time to complain!
快走
Quick!
我着火了  我着火啦
I am on fire!
别看了
God.
这可不是咱不仗义
It's not our fault.
这谁能有办法啊
There is no way to help them.
喂
Huh!
啊  都什么时候了
At this point,
爹死娘嫁人  各人顾各人吧
it is better to help ourselves first.
赶紧撤啊
Let's leave!
撤吧
Go.
走
石棉衣  快
Asbestos clothes.
我们走
Let's go.
走
Go.
歇会儿吧
Take a rest.
现在位置海拔负7米 位于山腹西西北292点3度
We are at minus 7 meters altitude, northwest 292.3 degree to the mountain.
地表火山口跟堰塞湖  东南侧
Southeast to the Yansai Lake and volcanic crater
那边有水声
Water sound over there.
找到地下河  咱们就能出去
We can get out if we find the underground stream.
走
Go.
哎  凯爷
Mr. Wang.
走啊
Let's go.
凯爷
Mr. Wang.
凯旋  杵那干嘛
What are you waiting for?
等结尾款啊
The fire to catch you?
这几个意思这是
What do you mean?
不是  都到这儿了
Are you really gonna leave?
你真打算要撤呀
We are already here.
我知道你在想什么
I know what's in your mind,
但是  过去的已经过去了
but the past belongs to the past.
人  应该往前看
We should look forward.
凯旋  走
Let's go.
你胡八一拿得起放得下
You let things go easily all the time.
我没你那么想得开
I can't.
我念旧
I do look back.
我王凯旋爱一个女人  我会记她一辈子
I love someone and I never let go.
老胡  我文采不如你  你帮我看看
I don't know too much about literature as you do, Hu. Help me with this.
你帮我看看
Please.
呦
Wow,
写诗
A poem
写情诗
of love.
别嚷嚷
Don't make fun of me.
你帮我瞅瞅
Would you check it?
写给谁的
To whom?
给谁的
Whom?
你帮我看看
Not telling.
王凯旋  写了一首情诗
Wang Kaixuan wrote a Love poem!
帮不帮我看  帮不帮我看
Are you helping me or not?
我帮
Yeah.
错别字儿
Misspellings here
here
错别字儿
and here.
你  你  你别管那个
Don't heed it.
额尔古纳河啊  你拐了个弯儿
E Er Gu Na River, you made a turn.
又溜达进了我的心里
Turn into my heart
这么着吧
Ok.
我胡八一决定亲自
I, Hu Bayi, decide to
帮你改一次
edit it for you myself.
怎么样
How about that?
够哥们儿
That's my bro.
兄弟都帮了你这么大忙了
Is there anything for your bro then?
你是不是得  表示表示啊
Who is helping you so much?
军星
The star badge.
去  想得美
No way!
哎  哎  哎
Oi oi.
真好看
It fits you.
小丁  其实我一直想跟你说
Ding, I've been resisting the temptation to ask
能不能把我们纯洁的革命友谊
if you are willing to sublimate
再升华一下
our innocent comradeship of revolution.
你想  怎么升华
In what way?
当我第一次看到你明亮的眼光
My heart started to stammer
我心灵的火花就开始迸放
when I first saw your bright eyes
啊
Oh
额尔古纳河  额尔古纳河
E Er Gu Na River
你映进了女峰的身影  滔滔流长
Your long run have flown into the mountain of goddess
不害臊
Idiot!
又流过了男峰的麓下  流进我的心房
Flown into the mountain of gods, into my heart.
王凯旋
Wang Kaixuan,
求求你别念了
Stop it please.
多不好呀
People would hear.
我这就是
I am just reading
有感而发
what I felt.
哟  军星
Wow, the star of the revolution.
哪儿来的呀
Where did you get it?
一、一个朋友送的
A...a friend gave it to me.
胡、胡八一呀
Hu... Hu Bayi?
你怎么知道
How did you know?
我知道小丁更喜欢你
I know Ding liked you more
但我不在乎
but I didn't care
为她做任何事  我都心甘情愿
I'm willing to do anything for her.
这些年我也记不清楚有多少个晚上
It has been a million times in years
我也不知道自己是醒着  还是睡着了
in night time, when I didn't know if I was awake or not
我就看见小丁的脸  就在我眼前
I saw her face in front of me.
就这么盯着我
Her looking at me
她问我找到彼岸花没有
asking if I've found the Equinox flower
我没法回答
I could not answer.
你也别忘了当初小丁是怎么死的
Don't you forget about her death.
跳
Jump.
你们先上
Get in.
快进去
胡八一  快上来
Hu Bayi, get in.
快  快
Be quick.
小丁
Ding
抓住
Hold on.
小丁  抓住
Hold on to it.
别松手啊
Don't let go.
不砍断那木头  咱仨都走不了
We'll all die if we don't cut the wood.
小丁
Ding
小丁  抓住
ding, hold on.
松开
Let go!
不要
No!
松手
Please!
回来  回来
Get back!
你要干嘛
What now?
小丁
Ding
跳
Jump.
小丁  跳啊
Jump. Ding.
不  不  不要  不要
No!
小丁  小丁
Ding!
小丁
丁思甜是为我们俩死的
Ding died for us.
这事我过不去
She really did.
都已经到这儿了  现在说要回去
We are finally here.
我做不到
How can I just take it easy and leave?
这个女孩子为了你们牺牲了自己
Ding sacrificed herself
就是要你们好好的活着
for you two to be alive.
我真的不懂
I really don't understand.
为什么还要跑回来送死
Why do you wanna come back and die here?
你当然不懂
Of course you don't.
我随时都可以为小丁去死
I'm ready to give up my life for Ding any moment.
这叫革命情谊
This is the comradeship of revolution.
要走你们走
Please go ahead if you wanna leave.
行
Alright.
我陪你去找彼岸花
I go with you for the Equinox flower.
让他们在这等我们
Let them wait for us here.
真的
No joking?
No joking.
我就知道你胡八一不是那么忘恩负义的人
I knew that you weren't an irresponsible man.
大老爷们
Real men
活就活个仗义
live for loyalty and honesty.
你们哥俩放心去啊  杨小姐就交给我了
Don't you guys worry about Miss Yang. I'll take care of her.
你放心
Don't worry.
我去去就回
I'll be back soon.
不送
Ciao.
走
Let's go.
胡八一  你这个说话不算话的大混蛋
Hu Bayi, you liar.
你们俩个就抱在一起去送死好了
You two can go to hell.
我再也不想见到你们了
I never wanna see you guys anymore!
甘洒热血写春秋
We live the days, the years by our blood and tear.
这就叫与天斗其乐无穷
We fight against the heaven,
与地斗其乐无穷
the earth,
与活人斗  与死人斗  其乐无穷啊
the living and the dead.
咱们终于又联手啦
We are fighting together as a team again.
对啊  其乐无穷啊
Yeah. It's fun, isn't it?
你干什么
What the fuck!
兄弟对不起啦
I am sorry bro.
道理你不听  我只能把你先绑回去再说
You don't listen to me and I can only use force.
又被你骗了
You son of a bitch.
你这是人吗
Are you a real man!
你把我放开
Let me go!
松手
Let go!
你当年就不该把我从地底下拉出来
You shouldn't have saved me at all.
我就应该死在底下  永远跟小丁在一块儿
So that Ding and I could be together forever
活也活不痛快  还不如死了的算
and no need to suffer for living.
胡说什么
Nonsense.
你还好意思继续活着
Don't you feel shameful living a life like this!
忘记过去就等于背叛
Forgetting is betraying
丁思甜已经死了
Ding Sitian is already died.
我不能再失去你跟Shirley
I can't lose you and Shirley.
无论如何  我得把你们俩活着带出去
I have to take you both out of here for whatever it takes.
你明白吗
Do you understand!
少跟我废话  你这个叛徒
Shut up you traitor!
你大爷的
Damn you!
我答应过小丁
I've promised Ding
一定要找到彼岸花
to find Equinox flower.
我说到做到
I meant it.
我跟你不一样
I'm not like you.
Shirley
Shirley.
老金
Grill.
胡爷
Mr. Hu.
Shirley呢
Where's Shirley?
我没用啊
I'm useless...
你们跑得挺快啊
You guys ran pretty fast huh.
Shirley在哪
Where's Shirley?
凯爷在此
Mr. Wang is here.
老胡
Hu!
走你
Here you go!
起
Go!
我去你的
Damn you!
去你大爷的
小丫头片子
Little bitch!
Shirley在哪  在哪
Where's Shirley?
都住手
Hold!
给我说清楚  听见没
Give me a clear, understand?
不要伤她  放下武器
Don't hurt her. Take your weapons down.
我们什么都好商量
Let's talk.
什么都好商量
There's nothing to talk about.
洋子
Yuko
放开我
Let me go!
都好商量
Chill.
好好商量
Take it easy.
别乱来
Calm down.
带我找到地宫
Find me the tomb.
你女朋友就一点事都不会有
Your girlfriend'll be safe.
我不是他女朋友
I'm not his girlfriend!
她是我女朋友
She is.
什么玩意儿  什么乱七八糟的
What the hell.
上过床不代表就是女朋友
Slept together doesn't mean that we are in a relationship.
上过床当然是女朋友
Slept together of course means we are in a relationship.
上  上床  上什么床
Slept...slept together?
你  你不天天
You...you
跟我睡一块儿吗
You sleep with me everyday.
这种事
It's not that complicated
插个空儿就办了
to have a quickie.
不不不不  我  我  我没弄明白你
No..I mean..What?
你什么时候睡的呀
When did you do that?
金盆洗手那天
The day we made the vow.
金盆洗手
What?
那天
That day?
那我抱着马桶  你俩在我眼皮子底下
The day I slept in the toilet and you two...
我说你这喝大了  占人姑娘便宜
Oh my god!
你个禽兽啊你
You are such a beast!
胡爷也是人嘛
Mr. Hu is also a human being.
他没占我便宜
He didn't take advantage of me.
是我把他睡了
I fucked him.
唉哟  你  你真是  女中豪杰啊你
Wow you are such a feminist!
还真不要脸啊你
Shame!
都给我闭嘴
Shut up!
你们这些缺弦少筋  后知后觉的蠢货
You idiots!
僕街  fucking  loser  ばか
Fuckin' loser!
狗日的你们这些狗日的龟儿子的
Have you got fuckin' enough
你们说够了没有
You fuckers!
你们是不是男女朋友  睡没睡过 我根本就不关心
I don't give a fuckin' shit about your relationships.
天机将至  抓紧时间  抓紧时间  抓紧时间
Don't waste my fuckin' time!
冷静
Calm down.
大姐
Lady.
我的罗盘毁了  寻龙诀没法儿使
My compass is broken so I can't use the 'dragon seeking' now.
反正世人即将全部毁灭
The world's going to be destroyed anyway.
我不介意先毁灭这一个
I don't mind destroying this one first.
大姐  我有办法
Lady, I have an idea.
前面两关  是我带大家过的
I've taken you get out of the traps.
您应该相信我
You should trust me.
但是我需要  我女朋友帮忙
But I need my girlfriend help me.
虽然罗盘毁了  但人体也能感应磁场
Human body could also sense the electrical currents
可以代替罗盘分金定穴 这种方法叫阴阳共济
To locate the tomb. It's called Yin-Yang-Gong-Ji.
这里
Here
有八座神像  它们不是随便摆放的
are eight statues and they're arranged in a specific way.
他们代表的是八卦
They represent Ba Gua.
咱都是死路一条了
It seems that we are gonna die...
我看这俩狗男女  又要搞什么么蛾子
I'm curious to see how the show goes on
咱们得赶快把绳子解开
We need to get rid of this rope.
寻龙分金看缠山  一重缠是一重关
To seek the Dragon through obstacles, each obstacle is a gate...
你真是个江湖骗子 道法沦坏器无用
You are such a swindler.
阴阳相济感应通
Synchronizing the Yin and the Yang...
寻龙不怕失龙踪
to form the constellations
还有观星认龙形
for searching the lost dragon...
干嘛呢
What are you doing?
没干嘛
Nothing.
你大爷
What the hell!
怎么这么大劲
You've got strength haven't you!
你腿没中枪啊
What? You didn't get hurt by the bullet!
中了  中了
I did I did.
它帮我挡了子弹呢
It protected me from the bullet.
你大爷的  怪不得你越来越沉
No wonder you are heavier!
他们只有一把枪
They've only got one gun.
我冲过去  你跑
I distract them, you run!
我挡  你跑
No you run.
我让你跑
I'm asking you to run!
你不走  我不走
I'm not leaving you alone here.
别别
Don't don't...
你大爷的
Damn you!
你过来
You come here!
快走
Run!
我说了  你不走我不走
I'm not leaving you.
孙子
You son of a bitch.
你骗我  骗我
You lied to me!
赶紧走
Leave!
把老子当驴骑
And rode me as your donkey?!
我弄死你
I'm gonna kill you!
这有条地道啊
Here's a tunnel!
我们这是在湖底
We are at the bottom of the lake
这壁画上说什么
Shirley, What does it say on the mural?
天开地裂  第一个萨满祭司受到神启
Heaven opened and Earth cracked.
得到了一件从天而降的宝物
The very first shaman received a sacred treasure from the gods.
它能够穿越阴阳两界  让人死而复生
It has the power to connect Yin and Yang, and to bring the dead back to life.
一千多年前  宝物落到了奥古公主手中
Princess Aogu obtained it a thousand years ago.
她将之命名为彼岸花
She named it “The Equinox Flower”.
每逢夙夜之交  彼岸花盛开
The “Equinox Flower” blooms every time the sun and moon unite.
生死之门就会被打开
And the gate between life and death will be open.
小丁说过
Ding said that
彼岸花能够连通生死
The Equinox flower's able to connect the living and the dead.
你就是为这个来的吧
You must have came here for this.
人类即将毁灭  这是最后的希望
Humanity is on the verge of destruction, this is the last hope.
只有我才可以拯救你们
I'm your only saviour.
只要得到彼岸花
If I can get the Equinox flower,
我就能把世人从死亡中拯救出来
I'll be able to resurrect people from the death.
谁要你个神经病去救啊
Who wants to be saved by a lunatic!
快走
Move!
别别别  别冲动
Calm down.
走
Move!
Let's go.
好好好  我们走  我们走
Ok ok.
她手里那个黑石头就是彼岸花呀
That black stone is the Equinox flower?
壁画上说从天而降
The mural shows that it fell directly from the Heaven.
应该是陨石
It could be a meteorolite
陨石  能解救众生
A meteorolite can save the world?
小心点
Be careful.
这三枚铜徽就是打开棺椁的钥匙  是吧
These three badges are the keys of the coffin, right?
不错
Yes.
干你们最拿手的
Do what you do best.
开棺吧
Open the coffin!
摸金校尉
Mojin Xiaowei,
合则生
United we stand,
分则死
Divided we fall.
这才是正宗的摸金范啊
That's it. The 'Mojin' Style!
彼岸花
The Equinox flower!
胡爷
Mr. Hu!
凯爷
Mr. Wang!
杨小姐
Miss Shirley!
Shirley
Shirley.
我们来过这儿
We've been here before.
老王
Wang,
你看
Look!
我去
Oh my god.
看那面旗子
Look at that flag!
隔了二十年
It's been twenty years,
转了一大圈
we've been in a cycle.
我们还是回到了这
We' re back to the start again...
虹大师啊  我求求您救救我这仨铁磁啊
Boss Hong, I beg you to save my best friends.
尾款我不要了  我不要了
Take back the final payment.
摸金一门不能全折在这啊
The Mojins can't all die like this!
你大爷的
Screw you!
小丫头片子
You little bitch
我今儿跟你丫拼了
I'm gonna educate you today!
你说彼岸花盛开都在夙夜之交
You said the Equinox Flower blooms in twilight?
对  按古人的时辰
Yes. According to the ancients,
也就是在寅时  早上的三点到五点
they often refer to Ying Shi, which is about 5 in the morning...
老王  二十年前出事的时候是几点钟啊
the incident happened 20 years ago, what time was it?
我记得咱们逃出来的时候
I remembered that right after we escaped from the base,
太阳快要升起来了
the sun soon came out.
还记得当年看见的光吗
Do you still remember the light we saw?
问题就出在这光上
It caused the problem.
光出现的时候
When the light appeared
鬼子就复活了
The dead soldiers came back to life.
光是从我们头顶照下来的
The light was from above.
那应该是棺椁里发出的光啊
It must be from the coffin.
不
No.
是神女手中的彼岸花发出的光
The light actually came from the Equinox flower.
我得救了
I am saved
彼岸花是我的
The Equinox flower is mine
现在就在寅时
It is Yin Shi.
大家撤出地宫
We should get out of the palace,
有危险
It's dangerous!
老金
Grill!
老金  走啊
Let's go, Grill!
大粽子
Zombies!
大粽子啊
全是大粽子
They are all Zombies!
别吃我
Don't eat me!
快跑
Run!
老金
Grill!
尊师
Master!
你走开
Get out of the way!
我不要你跟着我
I don't want you to follow me, get out!
我是你最忠诚的奴隶
I'm your Slave.
你为什么要抛弃我
Why do you abandon me?
救我
Save me
尊师
Master!
我没有法力
I don't have magic
我只有戒指里的麻药  还有很多钱
I only have anesthetics inside my ring, and a lot of money.
我救不了你
I can't save you
我活不了几天了
My life is doomed.
我脑袋里长东西了  治不好
There's something growing inside of my brain. There is no cure.
我需要彼岸花
I need the Equinox flower
我马上就要死了
I'm dying.
有了彼岸花
Only with the Equinox flower
我才可以获得重生
I may start a new life.
问题出在那块石头
It's that stone!
快去打碎彼岸花
Destroy the Equinox flower!
胡八一
Hu Bayi
抓紧  我们一起走
Hold onto me, let's go together!
我们还要在这里躺多久啊
How long are we gonna stay?
躺多久都行
As long as we wish.
什么花
What's this?
彼岸花
The Equinox flower.
传说只开在阴阳交界 有联通生死的神奇功能
Legends say that it transcends life and death.
没想到在草原上也有  我还是第一次见呢
I never knew that it would grow here.
小丁
Ding
我一直想跟你说
I always wanted to tell you
我
I...
我们
We...
我送你的像章
The star badge I gave you...
为什么是反的
Why is it reversed?
小丁
Ding!
胡八一
Hu Bayi
你要彼岸花吗
Do you want the Equinox flower?
打碎彼岸花  就再也见不到我了
You'll never see me if you destroy this.
你真的要这样做吗
Are you really going to do this?
你不是丁思甜
You are not Ding Sitian.
你是幻象
You are illusion.
不是真的
You are not real.
你只是我的记忆  我的恐惧
You are my memory,
你想要把我拉回过去
Dragging me back to the past.
难道你要忘了我吗
Are you going to forget me?
我不会忘记丁思甜
I won't forget Ding Sitian.
她牺牲自己
But she sacrificed her own life
不是要让我愧疚一辈子
Not to leave me in sorrow
是要让我好好活着
but to live in a meaningful life.
给我
Give it to me
老王
Wang
给我
Give it to me
放开
Let go!
把彼岸花给我
Give me the Equinox flower!
这彼岸花是小丁的
The flower belongs to Ding.
谁都不许碰
No one is allowed to touch it.
我找到了
I found it!
彼岸花我找到了
I found the Equinox flower!
我答应你的事情我做到了
I keep my promise.
从此以后
From now on,
即使我粉身碎骨
I will never let anything to hurt you,
我也绝不会让你再受到伤害
even if I die.
小丁
Ding.
你说的对
You were right,
彼岸花好美
equinox Flower is so beautiful.
王凯旋
Wang Kaixuan
把它给我
Give it to me
老王
Wang!
这都是幻觉
This is just an illusion.
假的
It's not real.
对小丁的愧疚
The guilty for Ding
是我们心里的执念
is but our obsession.
二十年了
It's been twenty years,
放下吧
let go of it
小丁
Ding
再见
Bye
老金
Grill!
大粽子  大粽子
Zombies! Zombies!
大粽子
Zombies!
老金
Grill!
大粽子
Zombies!
别跟着我
Don't follow me!
有了彼岸花
With the equinox flower
我就能起死回生
I can come back alive.
有了彼岸花
The Equinox flower...
我就能起死回生
I can come back alive
快走  危险
Run! Dangerous!
地宫的自毁装置启动了
The palace's self-destructive
洋子
Yoko
等着我
Wait for me
它只是块陨石
It's just a meteorolite.
发出来的光让人产生幻觉
Its light makes people hallucinate.
不会让人死而复生的
It doesn't bring the dead back to life.
闭嘴
Shut up
当心
Be careful!
地宫要塌了
The palace is about to collapse
快走
Hurry up!
快啊
Quickly!
别跟着我  别跟着我
Stop following me!
老金  你抓紧了
Grill! Hold me tight!
快跳
Jump!
山上的鹿被老虎吃了 老虎被黑熊追着累了
The deer is eaten by the tiger, the tiger is chased by the bear
阿妈  阿爸  水里有妖怪
Mum, Dad, there is a monster in the lake!
这下事儿可大发了
Oh my god it looks serious...
我们出不去了
We can't get out.
别愣着
Don't space out.
想辙呀
Think!
别瞎折腾了
Stop!
棺材
Coffin!
棺材有浮力
Coffins float!
可以把我们带出去
We can use them!
走
Go!
走啊
Let's go!
救命
Help!
粽子爷饶命
Master zombies! Please!
给我
Give me!
粽子爷饶命啊
Please!
来
Come on!
饶命
Please!
快
Hurry up!
别怕  有我在
It's okay. I'm here.
别废话  抱紧点
Shut up, hold tight.
我抽死你个大粽子
I will beat the hell out of you!
想吃我
Wanna bite me?
别废话  抱紧我
Shut up, hold me!
做你的青天白日梦
Go to hell!
我咬死你
I bite the soul out of you!
好像到了水面上
I think we are on the surface now.
我们还在地宫里
We are still in the underground palace.
我们被卡在石壁顶上的凹洞里了
We are stuck in the cavern on the rocky cliff.
用不了多久水就会淹没这儿
Soon we'll be drowned.
大不了一起死在这儿
A good way to end our lives.
你知道我最喜欢你什么吗
Do you know what I like you the most?
不知道
I don't know.
我最喜欢
It's the way
你骂我的样子
you yell at me.
你这么好的姑娘
It would be such a pity that
跟我死在这儿可惜了
a lovely girl like you to die here with me
胡八一
Hu Bayi!
胡八一  你这个王八蛋
Hu Bayi, you asshole!
你放我出去
Let me get out!
不是说好我们要死一起死的吗
You promised that if we die, we'll die together!
你让我出去  你让我出去
Let me out! Let me out!
我们要死就死在一起
We have to die together.
我就是要跟你在一起
I wanna be with you!
你这个不负责任的男人
You irresponsible asshole!
谁会喜欢你这种自以为是
No one would ever like such an arrogant
自作聪明
egoistic
又爱耍酷的混蛋
smartass punk like you!
我不要跟你死在一起  我不要
I don't want to die with you
我也不要梦到你
I don't want to dream of you
胡八一
Hu Bayi!
大粽子  有种你别跑
Zombies, don't try to run away!
你过来
Come here!
老金
Grill!
看好了  爷是谁呀
Look carefully, look who I am!
打你个大粽子
I'll beat the hell out of you zombie!
我今儿不灭了你
I'm gonna call you papa
我是你孙子
if I don't kill you today!
哎呀  我天
What the hell!
老胡
Hu!
孙贼
Hey you!
这回可真叫去五洋捉了鳖了
You are really swimming into the depth of hell aren't you!
你们这对狗男女
You dirty lovers!
老胡呢
Where's Hu?
说话啊
Say something!
你大爷的
Fuck!
就想自己当英雄永垂不朽是吧
You wanna be a hero and live in eternity?
没门儿
No god damn way!
出来
Get out!
我去下面拿了点东西
It took me a while down there.
耽误了一会儿
I went to get something.
你这大混蛋
You bastard!
耍什么酷啊你
Are you showing off again?
你骗我  你骗我  你不是说好要一起死的吗
Liar! Liar! You said that we would die together!
以后不许再扔下我一个人
You are not allowed to leave me alone from now on.
我真没用啊我
I'm so useless.
我连自己兄弟都救不了啊
I can't even save my bro...
你兄弟在这呢
Your bro is here!
你没死啊
You are alive?
你大爷的
Fuck you!
行了  我有正经事儿没办呢
Alright, something important needs to be done.
你还能有什么正经事儿啊
What important business would you have?
老老实实地过来  帮我做个见证
You come here and be my witness.
杨雪丽小姐
Miss Shirley Yang
你是否愿意
Would you like to
把我们纯洁的革命友谊
subliminate our innocent comradeship
再升华一下呀
of revolution ?
哟哟哟  这是要求婚呐
Are you proposing?
你这回还玩真的啦
You gotta be kidding me!
哪有人在棺材求婚的
Who's ever proposed in a coffin?
我的宝贝
My treasure!
喂
Hey!
嘿  纯金的
It's real gold!
还给我
Give me back!
这下我可发了
I'm gonna make a fortune!
小妹妹
Young Lady...
这你也敢抢
How dare you!
打得好
That was a good one!
老金你个孙子
Grill you bastard!
要不咱们回美国再说
Or shall we leave it till we get back to America.
你是不是爷们儿啊
Are you a real man?
你还真不要脸
You two are shameless!
胡爷
Mr. Hu.
杨小姐
Miss Yang.
大白天你耍流氓啊你
What the hell are you doing ?
王凯旋
Wang Kaixuan
凯爷  咱们又见面了
Mr. Wang here we go again.
你醒的还真是时候啊你
Good timing.
还以为再也见不着你们了呢
I thought I would never see you guys again
咱们是活着还是死了呀
Are we alive or are we dead?
这是在阴曹地府啊  还是在极乐世界啊
Are we in Heaven or are we in Hell?